<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on My Website</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on My Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ConocoPhillips Rod Pump Failure Dashboard</title>
      <link>/project/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project4/</guid>
      <description>Using ggplotly, here are the interactive machine learning results from the &amp;quot;Machine Learning: ConocoPhillips Rod Pumps&#39;&amp;quot; project. Read the project for interpretation of these results. Initially, this was a dashboard made with &amp;quot;flexdashboard&amp;quot;. I wasn&#39;t able to display the dashboard, so I put the interative plots here instead. If you want to see a copy of that dashboard, email me.
Everything is interactive! Make sure to click on the legends and different groups so you can see the difference between each failure type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rod Pump Failure Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project3/</guid>
      <description>Kapil Mangrolia
EID: kvm386
Introduction The dataset represents the rod pump failure in pumpjack systems. The dataset is from ConocoPhillips. It has various columns for characteristics of rod pumps and how they possibly failed such as sideload, inclination, start/end time, failure type, etc. The purpose of this project is to attempt to find hidden patterns on how/where the rod pumps are failing and then present the results. The first step in the analysis process is to clean the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>Kapil Mangrolia
EID: kvm386
Introduction The dataset is called &amp;quot;lakers&amp;quot; and is tidy and built into R. Lakers is a dataset that contains play by play statistics on the 2008-2009 Los Angeles Lakers. The 2008-2009 Los Angeles Lakers won an NBA Championship that year in a dominant and efficient manner. As a result, they are a great team to individually analyze. The dataset contains 34,624 rows and 13 columns. The data columns include the date, accronym of the opponent, and type of game (home/away game).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>Kapil Mangrolia
EID: kvm386
Introduction The NBA uses various statistics to analyze player&#39;s offensive and defensive performance. Using those statistics, predictions can be made on NBA players and how teams will perform in the future. However, what are the algorithms and statistics used to measure this? FiveThirtyEight is a wesbite with NBA data anaylyst that created the following two algorithms for this purpose: &amp;quot;RAPTOR&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;DRAYMOND&amp;quot;.
RAPTOR is a robust algorithm that uses &amp;quot;player tracking&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;on-off&amp;quot; statistics to determine how a player effects their team&#39;s offensive and defensive performance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
